Guide to the Donald Harris Papers, 1963-1964 and 2010 RL.11708
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Donald Harris Papers
1963-1964, 2010
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Harris, Donald (Donald Stuart)
RL.11708
0.5 Linear Feet
Donald Harris is a SNCC veteran and civil rights movement activist. This collection contains materials from his participation in SNCC including clippings, writings and articles, some ephemera, and other printed materials about SNCC.
Biographical / Historical
Donald Harris is a veteran of the civil rights movement. He joined the Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee (SNCC) in 1962 and became involved with voter registration efforts in Southwest Georgia, running C.B. King's congressional campaign in 1964. In August 1963, he and several other SNCC workers were violently attacked and jailed following a mass meeting at a church in Americus, GA. He was held without bail on charges of insurrection for three months before being released on November 1st, 1963.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Donald Harris Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2018.
Related Materials
Acquired as part of Duke's SNCC Legacy Project initiative. Additional archival collections from this initiative can be found through the library catalog.
Collection Overview
This collection contains materials from Don Harris's involvement in SNCC, particularly in SNCC-led voter registration efforts in Southwest Georgia during the early 1960s. Also included are legal and media documents regarding his arrest on insurrection charges in August 1963, and a report from a 1964 trip across the African continent. Contains SNCC buttons and brochures. Acquired as part of the John Hope Franklin Research Center at Rubenstein Library.
Civil rights demonstrations; Civil rights movements -- Southern States; Civil rights movements -- Georgia; Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee (U.S.); John Hope Franklin Research Center for African and African American History and Culture
- SNCC buttons, 1960s (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents
  5 buttons. 3 SNCC buttons, 1 Black Panthers button, 1 school desegregation button.
- The Crisis journal, 1963 Feb. (Box 1)
- Demographic fieldwork (American South) and voter registration flyer, 1963 Spring (Box 1)
- Don Harris arrest and SNCC demonstrations in support of release, 1963 Apr.-1963 Nov (Box 1)
  Civil subpoena, correspondence between SNCC organizers over demonstrations, event flyer, report on demonstration
- Media coverage of Don Harris's arrest, 1963 Apr.-1964 Apr. (Box 1)
  Magazine and newspaper clippings
- SNCC newsletters and special reports, 1963 Apr. 1-Sep. 24 (Box 1)
  Incl. information about activity in Americus, Georgia and Selma, Alabama; meetings, demonstrations, and arrests
- SNCC brochures, 1963 Aug. (Box 1)
- Account of arrest of Freedom Singers, 1963 Aug. 12 (Box 1)
- SNCC Southwest Georgia Project, 1963 Aug.-1964 Mar. (Box 1)
  reports, corespondence, fieldwork
- NAACP Legal Defense and Educational Fund annual report, 1963 Dec. 31 (Box 1)
- Clippings, 1963-1964 (Box 1)
  Newspaper and magazine coverage of SNCC activity
- Report from SNCC trip across African continent, 1963 Mar. 16-1964 Sep. (Box 1)
- SNCC 50th Anniversary Conference, 2010 Apr. 15-18 (Box 1)